<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>To the right vvorshipful the heads of the respective colleges and halls in the Vniversity of Oxford Sirs, you are desired to signify to your societies that whereas on Friday morning next thereis intended to be held a convocation in the theater for the University's being invested in the possession of it ...</title>
            <author>University of Oxford.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1669</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 5 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2012-10">2012-10 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B09663</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing O987L</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R181298</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">62369567</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 62369567</idno>
            <idno type="VID">188069</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B09663)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 188069)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2854:16)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>To the right vvorshipful the heads of the respective colleges and halls in the Vniversity of Oxford Sirs, you are desired to signify to your societies that whereas on Friday morning next thereis intended to be held a convocation in the theater for the University's being invested in the possession of it ...</title>
                  <author>University of Oxford.</author>
                  <author>Fell, John, 1625-1686.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.).   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by H. Hall, Printer to the University,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Oxford :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1669.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Signed: John Fell, vice-Chan of Oxford.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: Bodleian Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>University of Oxford --  History --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Sheldonian Theatre.</term>
               <term>Academic costume --  England --  Oxford --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  England --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2011-12</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2011-12</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-01</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-01</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2012-05</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="text">
            <pb facs="tcp:188069:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <head>
               <figure>
                  <head>ACADE<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>MIA OXONI<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ENSIS</head>
                  <q xml:lang="lat">SAP<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>IEN<g ref="char:EOLunhyphen"/>TIA <gap reason="illegible" extent="2 words">
                        <desc>〈◊◊〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </q>
                  <figDesc>blazon of the University of Oxford</figDesc>
               </figure>
            </head>
            <head>To the right VVorſhipful the Heads of the reſpective Colleges and Halls in the VNIVERSITY of <hi>OXFORD.</hi>
            </head>
            <opener>
               <salute>Sirs,</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>
               <seg rend="decorInit">Y</seg>Ou are deſired to ſignify to your Societies, that whereas on Friday morning next there is in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tended to be held a Convocation in the <hi>Theater,</hi> for the <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>niverſity's being inveſted in the Poſſeſſion of it: All perſons under the Degree of Maſters of Art, are to forbear to preſſe, and thereby make diſturbance.</p>
            <p>Withall you are deſired to enform them whom it may concern, that the riſing Semicircle of the Houſe, is reſerved for the Doctors and Noble men; and the whole Area for the Maſters of Art.</p>
            <p>You are farther deſired to let them know, that in the After-noon of the ſame day, there will be held the Encoenia or Dedication of the Houſe; where, as at all times during the whole Act: the aforeſaid Semicircle, will be the place of the Doctors, Noble men, and Inceptors in the ſuperior faculties. The Encloſure within the Rail, the place of Inceptors in Arts. The Gallery beyond the Doctors in the Circular part of the <hi>Theater,</hi> will be the place of Maſters. The ſide Gallery Weſtward is reſerved for the <hi>Cambridge</hi> men: That Eaſtward for Strangers. The Galleries in the Front for La<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dies and Gentlewomen. The <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>pper Gallery above the Maſters, is appointed for the Gentlemen Commoners and Bachelors. Thoſe above the <hi>Cambridge</hi> men and Strangers, for Commoners. That above the Ladies for performances of Muſick: The Area for Perſons of promiſcuous Quality.</p>
            <p>For preſerving of Order, there are, beſides the Curators of the <hi>Theater,</hi> appionted ſeveral Proctors of it; who, according to the Statute made in that behalf, are to take care that the publick Peace be kept undiſturb'd; and that all perſons be placed in their aforeſaid Stations; for whoſe aſſiſtance, there are aſsign'd ſeveral Officers and door-keepers, to be ſubſervient to them, and execute their commands.</p>
            <p>It is ſtrictly required, that during the time of the Act, all Perſons do appear in their Gowns and Caps: and particularly, all <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>ndergraduates, and Bachelors of Arts comport themſelves with that Sobriety and Modeſty as may tend to the Reputation and Honor of the <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>niverſity, upon pain of being enter'd in<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>to the black Book, and otherwiſe proceeded againſt as the exigence of their faults ſhall require.</p>
            <p>Withall it is required, that no perſon below the condition of a Gentleman or Fellow-Commoner, ſhall preſume to wear a Silk Cap; or pretend to a place beyond that which really belongs to him.</p>
            <p>And laſtly, it is Ordered that no Scholar reſident in the <g ref="char:V">Ʋ</g>niverſity, of what condition ſoever, ſhall be admitted upon any pretence into the <hi>Theater,</hi> who is not in his Gown and Cap.</p>
            <closer>
               <signed>
                  <hi>JOHN FELL</hi> Vice-Chan: of OXFORD.</signed>
            </closer>
            <postscript>
               <list>
                  <head>The Names of the Curators &amp; Proctors for the <hi>Theater,</hi> in the following Act.</head>
                  <item>
                     <list>
                        <head> Curators.</head>
                        <item>Dr. <hi>Yates,</hi>
                        </item>
                        <item>Dr. <hi>Ironſides</hi>
                        </item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
                  <item>
                     <list>
                        <head>PROCTERS.</head>
                        <item>Mr. <hi>Pullen</hi> of <hi>Magd: Hall,</hi>
                        </item>
                        <item>Mr. <hi>Herſent</hi> of <hi>New Col.</hi>
                        </item>
                        <item>Mr. <hi>Halſted</hi> of <hi>Braſenoſe,</hi>
                        </item>
                        <item>Mr. <hi>Fletcher</hi> of <hi>Corp: Ch:</hi>
                        </item>
                        <item>Mr. <hi>Martin</hi> of <hi>Chriſt Ch:</hi>
                        </item>
                        <item>Mr. <hi>Huntington</hi> of <hi>Merton,</hi>
                        </item>
                        <item>Mr. <hi>Hobbs</hi> of <hi>Magdalen,</hi>
                        </item>
                        <item>Mr. <hi>Robinſon</hi> of <hi>Queens,</hi>
                        </item>
                        <item>Mr. <hi>Whalley</hi> of <hi>Wadham,</hi>
                        </item>
                        <item>Mr. <hi>Field</hi> of <hi>Trinity.</hi>
                        </item>
                        <item>Mr. <hi>Edwards</hi> of <hi>Jeſus,</hi>
                        </item>
                        <item>Mr. <hi>Colliber</hi> of <hi>Exeter,</hi>
                        </item>
                        <item>Mr. <hi>Clerk</hi> of <hi>Lincolne,</hi>
                        </item>
                        <item>Mr. <hi>Thomas</hi> of <hi>Univerſ:</hi>
                        </item>
                        <item>Mr. <hi>Frampton</hi> of <hi>Pemb.</hi>
                        </item>
                        <item>Mr. <hi>Workman</hi> of <hi>Alſoules,</hi>
                        </item>
                        <item>Mr. <hi>Aſgill</hi> of <hi>S<hi rend="sup">t</hi> Johns.</hi>
                        </item>
                     </list>
                  </item>
               </list>
            </postscript>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>OX<gap reason="illegible" extent="1 letter">
                     <desc>•</desc>
                  </gap>FORD,</hi> Printed by <hi>H. Hall</hi> printer to the <hi>Univerſity.</hi> 1669.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
